To safely work online as a submissive, we must first understand the illusion of
control.
So although it may seem like it's the dominant in the relationship that has all
the control,
this is an illusion and it's understanding this which helps us to practise
safely online.
So although the dom is directing the play is coming up with them, ideas is
directing
the person and what you might do, the sub is holding the boundaries.
So it's you as a sub who will have hard limits, so things that you absolutely
won't do, which
should be discussed with the dom beforehand, such as maybe humiliation or rope
play.
If there's a certain element of submission that doesn't feel comfortable for
you, it's
okay to say no as a hard limit and that will never be an option.
You can also have soft limits, so things that you're not quite sure on as we
know day to
day, we might feel differently.
So something that feels okay on one day might not feel okay on another and
these are called
our soft limits.
If we have a safe word, which we know that we can use at any time to stop the
play, we
might also have amber words.
So if for instance if your safe word is red, you might say amber when something
is getting
a little bit too much and you're not quite sure about it and you want the
dominant to
tone it down a little, so it's always good to have a safe word and an amber
word, whatever
that is.
It's good to be aware that you as part of your role play and as part of your
sub-dom play
may say no to something and the dominant may continue to do it.
If that is the case, make sure that you say your safe word and make sure that
you've got
a safe word set up for this scenario.
Sometimes as part of the role play and as part of the excitement of the moment,
a dog
might like to say no and you might like to say no and have that no not listen
to, but
actually if it's safe and consensual then you should have a safe word which
when used
will stop the play completely at any time.
If a dominant gets angry with you or annoyed or frustrated because you've
either said an
amber word or you've said a safe word or you're not happy with what's going on
then
this is a plastic dom.
This is not somebody that knows what they're doing, they're not working in a
consensual
and safe way and you're better off ending the call than trying to continue.